We're providing you with an asset drop, view the link below,
so that you can download the images and include them in
the app. When we open up the assets ZIP file, we
see that the same icon is provided at different sizes for
different resolutions. In the drawable MDPI folder, we see the assets
that will be used on an MDPI device. In the drawable
HDPI folder, we see the assets that will be used on
an HDPI device. And the same goes for the other folders.
Under the res directory copy over all the asset
folders provided in the download. Clicking on an image shows
a preview of it and the size and pixels
is also shown. At this time you can also remove
the old placeholder ic launcher icons. Our new launcher
icons are located in mipmap folders. These are distinct folders
from the drawable folders. If you build an APK
for a target screen resolution like HDPI, the Android asset
packaging tool, AAPT, can strip out the drawables for other resolutions
that you don't need. But if it's in the mipmap folders,
then these assets will stay in the APK regardless of the
target resolution. But when would you need an image at a
resolution different than the resolution of the device? Well, one example
is the Android launcher app, which controls the home screen as
well as the All App store. The launcher app won't use
the icon at the current density of the device, but rather
pulls a icon for the next highest resolution up. For an XXHDPI device like the
Nexus 5, normally the assets will be pulled
from the drawable XXHDPI folder. However, in this
case the launcher icon will pull the XXXHDPI
version of the launcher icon. That will make
the larger app icons appear sharper on the
all apps screen. In the code replace @drawable/ic_launcher
with @mipmap/ic_launcher because of the new location of the icons.
For the rest of the icons modify the forecast list
and the details screen to display the right weather icon
instead of the placeholder one. See the hints below in
the instructor notes. Using the helper functions we've provided in
the gist below, you can map the weather condition code
to the icon that you'll need. This is what the
app should look like when you're done with this step.
Note that there are two types of each weather
icon, a gray icon and a colored art image.
In the main forecast list we'll be using the
gray icon. However, for the today layout, we'll use the
colored icon. When you go inside the detail activity,
you'll also use the colored icon. At this time,
you can also remove any images you hard coded
into the layout XML, because they'll be populated dynamically now.